

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211





Shankar K Shankar K Reatured Seeking roles in Software Engineering, Design Development, Application Support, Project Management, Change Management, Defect Management, Quality Management, Requirement Gathering, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Waterfall, JQuery, Agile, MySQL, HTML, ITIL, CSS, XML, PHP, C Current Designation: IT Specialist - Microsoft Development Total Experience: 10 Year(s) 0 Month(s) Technologies Notice Period: 3 Months Current Company: FLSmidth Private Limited Highest Degree: MCA[Computers] Current Location: Chennai Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore. Chennai. Coimbatore Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming / Maintenance Role: Tech Architect Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Key Skills: IT Specialist, Tech Architect, Software Engineering, Design Development, Application Support, Project Specialist, Tech Architect, Software Engineering, Design Development, Application Support, Project Specialist, Tech Architect, Software Engineering, Design Development, Application Support, Project Specialist, Tech Architect, Software Engineering, Design Development, Application Support, Project Specialist, Tech Architect, Software Engineering, Design Development, Application Support, Project Specialist, Tech Architect, Software Engineering, Design Development, Application Support, Project Specialist, Tech Architect, Software Engineering, Design Development, Application Support, Project Specialist, Spec

option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details withheld

· Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email

**Important** 

and attached resume of the candidates have been

Last Active: 22-Jan-21 Last Modified: 22-Jan-21

Gathering, JavaScript, JQuery, Agile, MySQL, HTML, ITIL, CSS, XML, PHP, C

Jump to Section

Marital Status: Married

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Management, Change Management, Defect Management, Quality Management, Requirement

## Summary

Having Around 10 years of working experience in various phases of SDLC.

Developing and maintaining multiple parallel projects

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Involved in design and development of Windows and Web Applications.

Excellent working knowledge of .Net Framework 3.5/4.xx and .Net Core.

Handling DevOps & Azure storages, Cosmo, Azure AD, Consuming Azure API.

Experienced frontend development with Angular 2.

Extensive working experience C#.Net,ASP.Net+MVC, MVM(WPF), Angular, ADO.Net, Linq, MVC, and WCF REST & Odata, Asp.net Web API services

Involved Sharepoint Development & Integrations.

To work with a dynamic organization that will grow from my contribution and also enable me to sharpen the skills acquired and get enriched beyond my job responsibilities. Quick learner and Self Motivated Team Player who works well with people at all levels

# **Work Experience**

FLSmidth Private Limited as IT Specialist - Microsoft Development Technologies Jul 2011 to Till Date

FLSmidth is a global engineering company based in Copenhagen, Denmark. Employing about 11,300 people worldwide, it provides the global cement and mineral industries with plants, machinery, services and know-how. FLSmidth is listed on the Copenhagen Stock Exchange and has offices in more than 40 countries worldwide.

Team size Role: Development Lead

: Asp.Net, C#.net ,WPF ,WCF OData , Web API , Sharepoint , Azure Environment

LinQ, Jquery, Teleriks, Azure Storage account, Net Core

Back-end: Sqlserver 2008.

Duration : jan 2015 To till now.

Description

CAPA is Global Web and Desktop Tool to corrective and preventive Actions . It can be used in both web and window applications .The intranet users can directly use the CAPA web, CAPA Offline can be used by remote site users. There are different source data from Atlas ,SAP ,Oracle and Epicor through ESB(enterprise service bus). It handles Projects ,PO and Tasks equipments. The CAPA Online is Sharepoint based web applications. The submitted CAPA item can be reviewed by controllers, and make further decisions/Actions. It consist of various application like CAPA Upload, CAPA Manual Upload and ODATA services and FIBS.

- Established integration between .Net services and Sharepoint Resources.
- Functionality to upload BU data from MS Excel.
- It allows an different role persons make specific action and access resources.
- Created and maintained wcf, ODATA services & classical web services

#### Responsibilities

Deployment incharge, creating deployment package & Task Scheduling. Requirement gathering in different data sources Atlas, SAP, Epicor and ERPs.

Mentor team

Design the Database tables based on entities.

Manage deliverables & Coordinate with SCRUMBased Development

Team size : 3 Role : Development Lead

Environment : ASP.net MVC 5 , ASP.Net Web API Controller , React.Js ,JQuery

WCF OData Services , WCF Interop services Back-end : Sqlserver 2012, Oracle 12g. Duration : Dec 2019 To till now.

Description

FIBS Stands for Financial Intelligence Business Solution . It is global automation support system designed for operating different finance system. The BOTS are designed to read the final output and handled raise the customer reports. It has been classified into six modules . Account payable , Account receivable ,E-collection , E-master ,E-Projects and E-Credit. We have done two modules so far and extended US ,Denmark ,Canada entities. The management can get reports (PowerBI) by our exposed ODATA services. The users can preview and validate the invoice before submitting to Customer.

#### Responsibilities

Deployment incharge, creating deployment package & Task Scheduling. Requirement gathering in different data sources Atlas, SAP, Epicor and ERPs.

Mentor team

Design the Database tables based on entities.

Manage deliverables & Coordinate with SCRUMBased Development

## Stira Technologies as Software Engineer

Dec 2010 to Jun 2011

SmarTek21(Stira) founded in 2006 is a global IT services company that helps enterprises solve development,

implementation and business problems.

TEAMSIZE : 12

Environment: Asp.Net, C#.net, Ajax, WCF, WCF REST,

LinQ, Silverlight, Jquery, Teleriks Back-end: Sqlserver 2008.

DURATION: JAN 2011 TO JUNE 2011. CLIENT: INTELLECTUAL VENTURES, WA, USA.

#### DESCRIPTION

This IV web based intranet application is used worldwide by intellectual Ventures. Intellectual Ventures is the global leader in the business of invention? creating new channels for inventors to realize value for their inventions, and creating invention advantage for companies that license with them. Intellectual Ventures purchases patents and patent applications from individual inventors, companies of all sizes, brokers and sellers, and then compiles them into industry-focused portfolios that are licensed to the world's most innovative companies.

RESPONSIBILITIES

- \* CREATING DATABASE AND IMPLEMENTING ADO.NET ARCHITECTURE.
- \* DESIGNING THE PAGES AND CODING
- \* UNIT TESTING AND DETAILED USER LEVEL TESTING OF THE APPLICATION.

Team size : 4

Environment : Asp.Net, C#.net ,Ajax Back-end : Sqlserver 2005. Duration : June 2009 to Oct 2009 Client : CBS business solution, Chennai Employer : Blackpearllogics, Coimbatore.

This web application product was developed for online command for entire company organization processes. It integrated with Reimbursement component ,Tax module , HR - Planning , Payroll processing ,Tracking . This MATRIMONIAL WEBSITE (WWW.HINDUSTANMARRY.COM) website has been developed for marriage assembling through web. It provides various user friendly functionalities to search life partner. Responsibilities

- \* Creating Database and Implementing ADO.Net Architecture.
- \* Designing the pages and coding

^ Back to Top

## Education

UG: B.Sc (Computers) from Arulmigu Palani Andavar College of Arts & Culture, Dindigul(MKU) in 2004 PG: MCA (Computers) from Sengunthar Engineering College, Tiruchengode, Anna University in 2007

^ Back to Top

### **IT Skills**

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
AngularJS ,Type Script ,JavaScript,	
JQuery, Angularjs , SQL Server , MySQL	
SSIS ,SSRS, Waterfall, Agile , C#	
PHP , Java ,Tomcat, SVN ,DevOps , Git	

# Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Tamil				

^ Back to Top

# **Affirmative Action**

# **Work Authorization**

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent / Temporary
Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.